Allison Brown

Software Developer

Phone: 647 648 1893

Email: allison.brown@hotmail.com

As a passionate and detail-oriented software developer, I bring a unique blend of skills and experiences from my background in education and healthcare. My journey into web development was sparked by my role at the University of Toronto Scarborough (UTSC), where I utilized Learning Management Systems (Canvas) to create engaging and effective learning resources for students. Since then, I have completed multiple courses and projects to develop and showcase my technical skills.

Education

React Bootcamp

Udemy

12/2023 - 04/2024

JavaScript Course

Juno College

02/2023 - 04/2023

Web Developer Bootcamp

Udemy

01/2023 - 12/2023

Master of Kinesiology

University of Toronto

2017 - 2019

Work Experience

Learning Skills Specialist

OCAD University

09/2023 - current

- Creating and managing digital learning content of LMS course (Canvas) for students on academic probation
- Developing and evaluating learning skills programming to assess efficacy and improve implementation
- Assessing student's learning skills and needs to develop individualized learning plans

Learning Strategist

University of Toronto Scarborough (UTSC)

09/2021 - 09/2023

- Collaborated with web developers and created digital learning content of LMS course (Canvas) for students with disabilities transitioning to university
- Created a learning skills website to provide self-serve resources for students with disabilities

Links

<u>Portfolio</u>

<u>GitHub</u>

LinkedIn

Technical Skills

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

jQuery

React

MongoDB

Express

Node.js

Git/GitHub

Responsive Design

WCAG guidelines

Professional Skills

Client-focused

Problem solving

Communication

Accessibility Counsellor

York University

12/2019 - 09/2021

- Interpreted medical documentation to recommend accommodations and assistive technology for students with disabilities
- Mediating conflict and fostering positive relationships between stakeholders (i.e.: faculty, students, admin)

Program Coordinator

University of Toronto

08/2018 - 04/2020

- Supervised and trained graduate kinesiology students on principles of motor learning and adaptive physical activity
- Developed and evaluated physical literacy program for children with disabilities